<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Predictive Modelling on Dhara Rawal</title>
    <link>https://dhararawal.github.io/Portfolio/tags/predictive-modelling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Predictive Modelling on Dhara Rawal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dhararawal.github.io/Portfolio/tags/predictive-modelling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Random Forest Model Titanic Survival Prediction Kaggle</title>
      <link>https://dhararawal.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dhararawal.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Predictive Model Built in Python:&#xA;Implemented a random forest model to predict passenger survival on the Titanic Achieved a 79% accuracy rate by Kaggle&amp;rsquo;s check Data Cleaning and Scaling:&#xA;Effectively used one hot encoding to recode variables ready for analysis Effectly dealt with missing variables via imputing the mean Packages used:&#xA;Used packages such as NumPy,Pandas, Seaborn and Matplotlib Coded using JupyterNotebook Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Predictive Modelling of Employee Attrition: Analysing Key Factors Influencing Attrition to Develop Targeted Retention Strategies</title>
      <link>https://dhararawal.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dhararawal.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Advanced Model Evaluation:&#xA;Implemented logistic regression, random forests, and support vector machine models for attrition prediction. Conducted rigorous model evaluation using ROC curves and area under the curve (AUC) metrics. Employed nested cross-validation to fine-tune hyperparameters and ensure robust model performance. Interactive Shiny Dashboard:&#xA;Developed an interactive Shiny dashboard for visualizing predicted attrition in real-time. Integrated dynamic data tables allowing users to filter data by department and explore employees predicted to be in attrition group 1.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
